Excuse me, sir.
I have a question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
I went broke because the state of Texas,
who I had a contract with, refused to pay me
and stole $30 million of my money.
I would never do business
with the state of Texas again.
What was the most amount of money
that you made this single year?
On a $6 million investment, I made like $40 million.
$600 million.
And what happened that year that you did $600 million?
Sold a business.
You sold a business.
How much did you sell the company for?
$600 million.
I'm 67, but I'm, you know, good.
I'm from 22, though.
You got 45 years on me.
Whose generation works harder, yours or mine?
Mine.
Yeah.
Why is that?
No question about it.
Do you think you worked harder
than me when you were my age?
Hell yeah.
What's one lesson about business that you give to somebody
that they will not learn in school?
Hard Knocks family, we are at the Millionaire's Playground
in Las Vegas.
And since Las Vegas is home
to 60,000 millionaires and over 10
billionaires, we're going to be going all over the city
to the wealthiest casinos, hotels, and restaurants
to figure out how the people here created their wealth
and how you can start your path to becoming financially
free.
And we're going to be
talking to some of the best
people in today's world.
So with that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Hard Knocks family, we just got to our first destination
out here in Las Vegas.
And we're at the Bellagio,
one of the most expensive hotels
for people to stay out here in Vegas.
So we're going to go up to the ballet,
see if we can talk to some of these millionaires,
figure out what they did to become
wealthy in today's world.
So come with us.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
What?
Broke?
Yeah.
Ha, no, man.
Let me show you a picture of my car.
Yeah.
That's a Lamborghini.
Wait, real quick, real quick.
What line of business are you in?
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah?
Could I interview you real quick?
What's this for?
I started a channel in Austin.
I grew it to 8 million followers.
I interviewed business owners.
OK, what do you want to know?
I guess, what line of business are you in?
Real estate.
What type of real estate?
Shopping centers.
I bought two of them in Las Vegas.
You said you bought two of them in Las Vegas.
Yeah, yeah, I just bought them.
How long have you been buying real estate for?
35 years.
There's a big misconception that you
have to have a ton
of money to start creating wealth
in real estate with.
No.
No?
So how do you get the money to buy assets?
Start small.
With what?
I started buying houses.
And I just kept building it up.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Now I just bought one on East Flamingo.
I paid $25 million.
Now I'm buying one on
the north side for about $20.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
Not one year, but one deal.
On a $6 million bed.
I made like $40 million.
$40 million.
On a $6 million investment.
As a millionaire, what's the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your career?
If there's a lesson about money.
That's a tough one.
If one lesson about money a mentor taught you
that always stuck with you.
I don't know.
A lesson?
Just be cautious.
Be cautious.
Because when someone's selling something,
they're getting rid of a problem.
And you have to find out what the problem is.
And then you have to create
a strategy of how to exit that.
You know, when you buy it,
how to make money and get out.
Every single deal they're selling,
remember they're selling.
Their problem to you.
Wow.
Yeah.
What is the lesson about money that banks
don't want people to know?
You never tell the bank everything.
When the banks ask me for my financial statement,
I always leave shit out.
Because they just want to
know everything, gobble it all up
if there's a problem.
Just tell them what they want to hear.
How old are you now?
I'm old.
I'm 67.
But I'm good.
I'm 22, though.
So you've got 45 years on me.
My kids are 10 years old.
Let me ask you this.
You've got 45 years on me.
Whose generation works harder, yours or mine?
Mine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Why is that?
No question about it.
These kids are on the computers.
They want to do quick things.
It takes time.
Got to work hard, stay focused.
These kids, you're 22 years old.
You want, you want, you want.
Do you think you worked harder
than me when you were my age?
Hell yeah.
Yeah.
I disagree with that.
I work a lot.
When I was 22 years
old, I had two jewelry stores.
I was hustling on the streets selling jewelry,
wholesaling, retailing, traveling, going to Italy
to buy this shit, coming back.
And we did it on a shoestring.
You've got amazing advice here.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate that.
Guys, we just interviewed a real estate mogul
who owns hundreds of millions
of dollars worth of real estate.
And he's had that hustle mentality in him
ever since he was a
young guy, going around the world
selling jewelry.
That work ethic never left him.
But my biggest takeaway from that interview
is that he's playing a completely different game
than everybody else.
See, there's a big misconception in real estate
that the bigger the deal,
the harder it is to do.
But in reality, it's the complete opposite.
The bigger the deal, the easier it is to do.
The people involved are smarter, the financing's easier,
and you can make a
hell of a lot more money.
Great interview out here in Las Vegas, you guys.
We're going to keep this video rolling.
Go get this next one.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Good question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Hell yeah.
Every hustler's been broke.
It's how you respond.
And what line of business are you in?
I'm in apparel.
Are you a business owner?
Absolutely.
I do manufacturing as well
as I have a clothing line.
And how long have you been an entrepreneur for?
10 years.
We're going on 10 years now.
Over these 10 years, what's the greatest lesson
that you've learned about entrepreneurship
that you pass on to someone about to start
their first company in today's world?
You've got to stay 10 toes down.
You know what I mean?
This isn't for everybody.
Let's just make sure that everybody
knows that, right?
And you've got to know that you're
trying to build a long-term brand.
You've got to be in it for the long haul.
You've got to be able to
have a strong foundation in terms
of what you're trying to build, making sure
that you've got a great team.
And then you have a long-term vision for the brand
of what you're trying to do.
You know, Jay-Z said, man, are you a trend
or are you Ralph Lauren?
You know what I mean?
I want to be around 50 years.
You feel me?
Yeah, he also said, I'm not a businessman.
I'm a business.
I'm a business, man.
Come on.
You know that.
That's deep right there.
That's game.
Real game.
Now, let me ask you this.
You've got to know exactly what you're manufacturing
the actual designs for and then what you're actually
going to sell it for.
Fortunately enough, we did the Nordstrom deal, right?
So there's bigger margins there based off
of us manufacturing overseas.
However, as I mentioned, we are manufactured here.
So we do screen printing and
direct to Garmin and DCF, right?
So our margins is bigger
because now I'm the actual printer.
So there's pride in that.
I grew up in the hood.
I'm from LA.
I'm from Carson.
You don't come from a lot of money.
I don't.
I never did, right?
And again, I speak, let's contextualize it.
As a Samoan, Polynesian, growing up
in Los Angeles, it's not common within my specific culture
to have successful entrepreneurs.
So when we did the
Nike deal or the Nordstrom deal
or pop up to Macy's and
Tilly's, this is the first time
it's ever happened.
It was 2024.
So I know I'm trailblazing
the path for a community that's
never done business at this level.
Why?
Because they don't have the relationships,
nor do they have the business
structure ready to go once you
do get the deal.
And remember, too, I tell entrepreneurs all the time,
that could be a gift and a curse.
You get the purchase order for 100 racks from Nordstrom,
and it takes you 50 racks.
You can actually do it.
Well, where's the 50 racks, James?
You're supposed to come up with that, right?
So you've got to make sure
that you have all your ducks
in a row in order
to play in the big leagues.
So what was the turning point in your life
that made you want to get really serious about becoming
financially free and building a clothing empire?
If there was one moment that you're like, man,
I want to get really
serious, what was that turning point?
My son is here.
He's 24 years old.
So as a father, I knew
that raising my son, at some point,
I wanted to pass on generational wealth to him
because I didn't come from that.
But then I had to figure out the game.
I had to build relationships.
And affluent communities, this is
why I'm at a conference now.
I really am a proponent of you've got
to go where the action is at.
And if it's not in the
hood, if it's not in your community,
you've got to literally go live with them.
Because more often than not, in these affluent communities,
that's where business owners is at.
Success is about proximity.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a
single year across all your businesses?
Let's just say seven figures.
Yeah, let's just say seven figures.
I don't like to go into the numbers.
Let's just say seven figures.
What's one lesson about business that you give to somebody
that they will not learn in school?
Relationships.
I always have to go back to relationships.
More often than not, this is what I learned
from a lot of my mentors, most successful entrepreneurs
at a high level want to
do business with people they like.
People buy from people they like.
Exactly.
And one of my guys said, despite the price.
I got one for you.
Price is only an issue if value is absent.
Oh, man.
He giving me a game now.
I'm taking that one.
Hey, hey, you got amazing advice, my friend.
I appreciate that.
That was exceptional.
Thank you, my boy.
Appreciate you, man.
All right, you guys, Las
Vegas has been insane so far.
And the best interviews are yet to come.
But I want to take a
quick moment to talk to you guys
about something that's been game changing for me
while I've been running this channel.
See, I've learned that 45% of millionaires in the United
States have some form of a side hustle,
where they're making additional money at all times.
That's why I want to talk
about the sponsor of today's video,
PrizePix.
Whether you work in a 9
to 5 or running your own business,
PrizePix gives you the ability to make some extra money
while you're already on the grind.
If you're into sports like I am and you're already
playing fantasy football, you might as well
learn how to turn that
passion into something that pays off.
Or as I like to
call it, turning passion into profit.
With PrizePix, it's never been easier.
All you have to do is
pick two or more football players,
pick whether they'll exceed or fall
short of their projected stats for that week,
and lock in your entry.
You're already keeping track of your favorite players
and their stats, so why not make some extra money
while you're doing so?
With a few smart picks and strategic decisions,
you could turn $10 into
$1,000 in a matter of minutes.
Head over to PrizePix using the link down
in the description of this video.
Use code SOHK for a guaranteed $50 bonus
when you put $5 into play.
With that being said, let's get back to the video.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
$600 million.
And what happened that year that you did $600 million?
Sold a business.
You sold a business?
How much did you sell the company for?
$600 million.
And what company was that?
It was INX.
Yeah?
Did you start that company?
With my brother and a few other guys, yeah.
We sold it to Presidio out of New York.
So have you ever been broke before?
Oh yeah.
What was the turning point to financial freedom?
No, no, you mean, okay, after I went broke?
Yes.
Ah, I went broke because,
the state of Texas, who I had a contract with,
refused to pay me and
filed a sovereign immunity against me
and stole $30 million of my money.
It's all over the news, everybody knows about it.
Would never do business with the state of Texas again.
Because they take your money, because they're sovereign.
Everybody, if you're an attorney, you know about this.
So what you do is
you have to put it down
like a speeding ticket, start the next day, brand new,
it's not your fault, and go make your money.
Let's say you're in a negotiation,
you're at the table with that person,
and it's not going your way.
Any tactics or something that you've kind of used
or that you've noticed that really helps
when you're selling or negotiating with somebody
with a prospective client for that matter?
Sure, if I had a client,
I was trying to get him as a customer,
and it was very difficult,
I'd get him to walk away.
I would fire that customer.
Because relationships are too important.
If you got it on the front end,
and the relationship starts out good,
then work it and be respectful to the relationship.
If it's so difficult,
if it's on the front end,
you can't get past the first stage,
fire them and move on,
because there's a lot of good people out there.
That's incredible.
What's a lesson about money
that banks don't want people to know?
That they're stealing from you every day.
What do you mean by that?
Oh my God, every time they take money from you.
They borrow money from the feds at zero, right?
As example.
They sell it to you at 10%.
They hit you with fees, right?
Then they tell you you're not qualified
because you don't make
enough money, right?
So they want you to increase.
It's just this vicious cycle.
Somebody has $100,000 right now.
What's the first step that you would take
if you had $100,000
and you want to start
making some money in real estate?
What are you buying?
I don't buy residential real estate.
So that's not a fair question for me.
Why not?
I just don't believe in residential real estate values.
I mean, if you go,
I think you buy a
home for you to live in
and raise your family, right?
It's, there's a lot of people that flip them
and things like that,
which is okay.
That's not really my business.
I do strictly commercial.
Right.
Why is commercial real estate your vehicle?
The bigger the deal,
it's a lot easier.
May take a little longer,
but you've got the professionals and the team
and the time to pull
it off and do it right.
So what type of commercial real estate
should people be looking to buy right now?
The federal government's got 14,000 buildings
that are empty.
Commercial is going to be an interesting market
in the next 20 years.
How old are you?
As of last month.
What's the deepest life quote that you've ever heard?
Never say never.
Your life's not for sure.
Your business is not for sure.
Your relationship's not for sure.
Your health is not for sure.
Right?
The only thing that's for sure is that guy.
It's all about that vertical line we draw with God.
Let me tell you, if
Jesus is not in your backbone,
you got a long way to go.
You better get to it.
Wow.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you so much for your time.
Well, I hope I did.
Las Vegas was incredible, you guys.
We just interviewed some of the craziest
eight and nine figure entrepreneurs
that are in this city right now.
But I want you guys to like and subscribe
for amazing content we've got coming very soon.
And click the link down
in the description of this video
to join our private entrepreneur community,
the School of Mentors,
where you can get directly mentored
from the multi-millionaires and the billionaires
that I interview on this channel every single week.
If you want to learn skills like how to sell,
how to market, how to create wealth in real estate,
how to start and grow businesses
directly from the millionaires you see on this channel,
go to the link down in the description
to join our private entrepreneur community.
I can't wait to see you on the inside.
But with that being said,
we'll see you in the next video.